A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries xFA118
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Marshall, John
  - 1936 August 20-December 31 (Box 291, Reel M Mar 1, Frame 955)
    Diaries; Film; Educational broadcasting; Language and languages; Music; Broadcasting; United States; Humanities; Radio in education; Libraries; Education; France; Radio; League of Nations; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; CBS Broadcasting Inc; National Broadcasting Company; Carnegie Corporation of New York; British Broadcasting Corporation
  - 1937 January 7-July 30 (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 1, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on creating a greater means of cultural diffusion. Grants were primarily made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall attends various conferences of the Federal Radio Education Committee, and the School and College Conference on English. The Worldwide Broadcasting Foundation’s experiment in developing radio program of cultural and education value with the W1XAL radio station is detailed as well.
    Humanities; Radio; Broadcasting; Radio in education; Educational broadcasting; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John; National Broadcasting Company; CBS Broadcasting Inc; British Broadcasting Corporation; United States. Federal Communications Commission
  - 1937 September 2-December 31 (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 217, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on creating a greater means of cultural diffusion. Grants were primarily made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall travels to University of Wisconsin and University of Minnesota. He attends the Conference on the Stratford Language Arts Study. The progress on various radio broadcasting projects as well as motion picture projects is documented.
    Diaries; Radio in education; Broadcasting; Motion pictures; Film; United States; Canada; Humanities; Radio; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; British Broadcasting Corporation; National Broadcasting Company; Marshall, John
  - 1938 January 4-December 29 (Box 292, Reel M Mar 2, Frame 356)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on the democratization of culture and the improvement of international communication through grants made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall travels to Europe to explore library activities and survey film and radio projects as well as surveys the relations of World Wide Broadcasting Foundation, Harvard University and Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
    Denmark; Finland; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Sweden; Radio; Broadcasting; Film; Motion pictures; United States; Libraries; Educational films; Drama; Switzerland; Norway; France; England; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1939 January 3-June 26 (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 607, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on the democratization of culture and the improvement of international communication through grants made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents the progress on various film and radio projects.
    Broadcasting; Film; Motion pictures; Radio; Humanities; Diaries; United States; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1939 July 5-December 27 (Box 292, Reel M Mar 2, Frame 770)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on the democratization of culture and the improvement of international communication through grants made to museums, drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents the progress on various film and radio projects. He also attends an informal conference on Motion Pictures in Latin America.
    Motion pictures; Film; Television; Radio; Humanities; Broadcasting; United States; Latin America; Diaries; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1940 January 2-June 26 (Reel M Mar 2, Frame 871, Box 292)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The grants of the humanities program center on the uses of print, film, radio and drama for effective communication.
    Radio; Motion pictures; Broadcasting; Diaries; Humanities; Film; United States; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; National Broadcasting Company
  - 1940 July 8-December 31 (Reel M Mar 3, Frame 1, Box 293)
    United States; Film; Broadcasting; Radio; Diaries; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1941 January 6-June 30 (Box 293, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 182)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The grants of the humanities program center on the uses of print, film, radio and drama for effective communication. Marshall attends various conferences on communication research, available multilingual personnel and intelligence services.
    Broadcasting; Diaries; Radio; Language and languages; Motion pictures; Film; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1941 July 1-December 31 (Box 293, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 475)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an assistant director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The grants of the humanities program center on the uses of print, film, radio and drama for effective communication. The various interviews include humanities program updates, fellowship progress and determination of grant applications.
    Humanities; Motion pictures; Film; Diaries; United States; Canada; Broadcasting; Radio; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1942 January 2-June 24 (Box 293, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 686)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on creating a greater means of cultural diffusion. Grants were primarily made to foreign language studies in support of the war effort, regional studies of North America and continued support to drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Cornell University to survey the English department, discuss plans for a summer workshop and studies on New York State regionalism. The New School for Social Research’s project on Totalitarian Communication in Wartime is documented as well.
    Diaries; Motion pictures; Radio; Libraries; Broadcasting; Education; Humanities; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1942 July 1-December 31 (Box 293, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 854)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program focuses on creating a greater means of cultural diffusion. Grants were primarily made to foreign language studies in support of the war effort, regional studies of North America and continued support to drama, film and radio. In this diary Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He surveys various universities in North America, locates talent for regionalism prong of Rockefeller Foundation Humanities program and discusses library assistance.
    Canada; Radio; Humanities; Drama; Education; Libraries; Diaries; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1943 January 1-June 30 (Box 294, Reel M Mar 3, Frame 990)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The division focuses on studies in foreign languages, American studies, drama, film and radio. Marshall documents current and future projects. He surveys programs in language and culture of Latin America and East Asia, and Slavic studies. Rehabilitation of European libraries after the war is discussed. He visits Vermont as part of the Rockefeller Foundation’s American regionalism program and attends various conferences and workshops.
    Libraries; Diaries; Vermont; Education; Humanities; Microfilms; Drama; Motion pictures; Film; Radio; Canada; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1943 July 1-December 31 (Box 294, Reel M Mar 4, Frame 1)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The division focuses on studies in foreign languages, American studies, drama, film and radio. Marshall documents current and future projects. The development of Cornell University’s Slavic studies program is detailed as well as rehabilitation programs for libraries abroad. He attends the Conference on the Humanities in American Institutions and travels to Quebec and Cleveland, Ohio.
    Diaries; Humanities; Libraries; United States; Canada; Slavic studies; Russia -- Study and teaching; Radio; Broadcasting; Motion pictures; Education; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1944 January 3-May 31 (Box 294, Reel M Mar 4, Frame 187)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. Grants were primarily given for the study and reorganization of academic disciplines, studies in American and Far East culture and language, drama radio and film. Marshall documents current and future projects. Organization of library centers in China, Mexico and South America is detailed as well as a discussion with the Library of Congress for library rehabilitation in London. Provisions for restoration of objects of art in war areas are documented as well as a Commission on the Function of Philosophy in Liberal Education.
    Slavic studies; Diaries; Language and languages; Education; Radio; Humanities; United States; Philosophy and religion; Drama; Motion pictures; Film; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1944 June 1-December 21 (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 400, Box 294)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The contents include meetings about various cultural relations programs. Discussions with the Joint Committee of National Library Associations, ACLS Committee on the Protection of Cultural Objects in War Areas and the American Library Association Committee are detailed regarding aid to libraries in war areas and book campaigns for European libraries.
    Film; Europe; Education; United States; Humanities; England; Broadcasting; Radio; History; Motion pictures; Drama; Libraries; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1945 March 19-June 29 (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 604, Box 294)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, film, radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects.
    Encyclopedias and dictionaries; Education; Libraries; Drama; Humanities; United States; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1945 July 2-December 27 (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 744, Box 294)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Europe to assess various interests in humanities. He surveys humanities education in the Baltic States. A report on Norway is included.
    United States; Diaries; Sweden; Motion pictures; Film; Humanities; England; Netherlands; Belgium; Denmark; Norway; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1946 June 3-September 27 (Reel M Mar 4, Frame 882, Box 295)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama film, radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects.
    Motion pictures; Libraries; Diaries; Humanities; Film; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1946 October 1-December 30 (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 1, Box 295)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to France to surveys the country’s humanities interests. A report on the Unesco General Conference held in Paris is included.
    United States; France; Linguistics; Diaries; Museums; Education; Drama; Folklore; Motion pictures; Libraries; Humanities; Film; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1947 January 2-March 31 (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 217, Box 295)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio and library assistance. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Europe and library restoration is detailed.
    Museums; Motion pictures; Education; Humanities; Film; Libraries; England; France; Diaries; Norway; Sweden; United States; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1947 October 1-December 31 (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 583, Box 295)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama and radio, libraries and museum assistance and research and education grants in the humanities. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. He travels to Europe and Mexico. Marshall assesses Mexico for Rockefeller Foundation assistance in international book supply and attends the Unesco general conference.
    Norway; Denmark; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Belgium; Motion pictures; History; Language and languages; Museums; Libraries; Mexico; France; Education; Humanities; Diaries; Film; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1948 January 2-May 5 (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 753, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies and drama. Marshall documents current and future grant projects. The Unesco Pilot Project in Fundamental Education is detailed.
    Haiti; Humanities; Film; Motion pictures; United States; Puerto Rico; Diaries; Education; Libraries; History; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1948 May 6-August 31 (Reel M Mar 5, Frame 938, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies and drama. Marshall documents current and future grant projects.
    Diaries; Theater; Ballet; Puerto Rico; Humanities; Radio; Drama; United States; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1948 September 1-December 29 (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 1, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The contents include Conference on Current Work in Language Teaching, a Pilot Project in Fundamental Education in Haiti and Marshall travels to the Middle East from 10 November- 17 December 1948 to represent the Rockefeller Foundation at the Third General Conference of Unesco.
    Humanities; Education; Language and languages; Cultural history; Broadcasting; Libraries; Film; Lebanon; United States; Middle East; Syria; Diaries; Motion pictures; Japan; Turkey; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1949 January 3-April 2 (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 225, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, radio and film. The diary details Marshall’s attendance at the Committee on Near Eastern Studies of the ACLS in Washington D.C. and at the Advisory Committee on the Japanese-Korean Broadcasting Project. He travels to Haiti for the Unesco Pilot Project in Fundamental Education and includes a report of his impressions on Puerto Rico from a 28 February- 3 March 1949 trip.
    History; Language and languages; Haiti; Humanities; United States; Puerto Rico; Museums; Film; Motion pictures; Theater; Libraries; Cultural history; Drama; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1949 April 4-August 31 (Reel M Mar 6, Frame 430, Box 296)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, radio and film. The diary details Marshall’s attendance at the Southern Humanities conference at the University of North Carolina; the Meeting of the Committee on the Japanese and Korean Broadcasting Project; the Meeting of the American Association of University Presses; Conference on Comparative History; Seminar on Educational Radio at the University of Illinois; and the Conference on World Understanding Through the Arts.
    Diaries; Microfilms; Education; Museums; Radio; Philosophy and religion; Film; Motion pictures; Broadcasting; Libraries; United States; History; Humanities; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1949 September 1-December 30 (Box 297, Reel M Mar 6, Frame 607)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The program’s focus is on studies in language and foreign culture, American studies, drama, radio and film. Marshall attends the Unesco General Conference and gives his impressions of the conference and assesses future relations between the Rockefeller Foundation and Unesco. He also attends the Rocky Mountain Radio Council in Denver, Colorado; the National Conference on Human Rights; and the Conference of the Committee on Education Reconstruction of the UN National Commission for Unesco. Marshall details a study of the Wisconsin region and surveys general education in the humanities program at the University of Syracuse.
    Diaries; France; United States; Broadcasting; Radio; Humanities; Human rights; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1950 January 3-May 17 (Box 297, Reel M Mar 6, Frame 855)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The Humanities Program is reorganizing its grant programs into “Language, Logic and Symbolism” representing general interest grants in communication, and “Intercultural Understanding” promotes research and interpretative work aimed at making cultures more understandable. Marshall visits Canada, Princeton University and attends the National Theater Conference.
    Canada; Humanities; United States; Dramatists; Slavic studies; Language and languages; Diaries; Theater; Drama; Radio; Broadcasting; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - Trip to Near East, 1950 April 17-May 17 (Box 297, Reel M Mar 6, Frame 1,010)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The contents include Marshall’s trip to the Near East to assess if humanities projects in the Middle East could be related to Rockefeller Foundation interests.
    Diaries; Libraries; Culture and Intellectual History; Education; Iraq; Humanities; Iran; Syria; Egypt; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.; Marshall, John
  - 1950 May 18-August 11 (Box 297, Reel M Mar 6, Frame 1,115)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The contents include notes on the Fifth General Conference of Unesco, Conference on Arab Outlook held at Harvard University and the Harvard Summer Institute.
    Humanities; France; Italy; Libraries; Playwriting; Diaries; Dramatists; Theater; Drama; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - 1950 September 19-December 31 (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 1, Box 297)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. Marshall discusses humanities grants with hopeful applicants and receives progress reports on current projects. He surveys the University of California at Los Angeles Department of Theatre Arts. He attends various conferences including the New School for Social Research’s Conference on Economic Development Abroad; Young Playwrights Committee Meeting; Meeting of the Writers in the IIE Young Artist Exchange Program; and the Regional Conference of the National Commission of Unesco in Havana, Cuba.
    Dramatists; Libraries; Education; Motion pictures; Film; Cuba; Humanities; Diaries; Theater; Drama; United States; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Index, 1951-1958 (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 221, Box 298)
    33 pages
  - 1951 January 2-March 18 (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 254, Box 298)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. John Marshall is an associate director of the Rockefeller Foundation’s Humanities Division. The Humanities Program is reorganizing its grant programs into “Language, Logic and Symbolism” representing general interest grants in communication, and “Intercultural Understanding” promotes research and interpretative work aimed at making cultures more understandable, and “Humane values” such as creative writing, literature, history, philosophy and work in the other arts. Marshall attends a meeting of ACLS.
    Diaries; Theaters; Drama; Humanities; United States; Motion pictures; Film; Marshall, John; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Humanities.
  - Trip to Near East, 1951 February 16-March 18 (Reel M Mar 7, Frame 334, Box 298)